https://britishdams.org/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
Institution of Civil Engineers & Thomas Telford Ltd Privacy Notice
This Privacy Statement sets out how the British Dam Society (BDS) uses and protects any information that you give the BDS when you use this website. This is in compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), which came into effect on 25th May 2018.
The BDS is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this Privacy Statement.
The BDS may change this Statement from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This Statement is effective from 29th May 2018.
The BDS is a learned society within the Institution of Civil Engineers (ICE).
Data Controller
The data controller can be contacted as follows:
Data Controller,
The Institution of Civil Engineers,
One Great George Street,
Westminster,
London,
SW1P 3AA
Telephone 0207 665 2146
Email: dataprotection@ice.org.uk
Use, transfer and storage of personal data
We may hold any of the following items of personal information about you:
Personal details including your name, ICE membership number, gender, date of birth, postal and email addresses and telephone number,
Employer name,
Other information relevant to bookings and / or membership surveys,
Membership details and preferences.
The Institution of Civil Engineers and Thomas Telford Ltd maintain data on all BDS members.
We use this information for the following purposes:
Provide our members with news via society newsletters (unless you have requested that you do not wish to receive this information),
Provide event notifications for example our meetings and conferences (unless you have requested that you do not receive this information),
Inform the membership regarding the Committee, Sub-Committees, Working Groups, elections etc,
To forward news, information and technical bulletins from the International Commission on Large Dams (ICOLD).
Data relating to attendance at our conference events may be stored in perpetuity.
We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.
Security
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable equipment and processes to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.
Cookies
We use tracking cookies on our website to:
Provide us with information as to the pages visited and time spent on each page,
Allow customisation of the website (eg retaining information for your log on and purchasing pages),
These cookies do not allow us to identify you.
Cookies can be turned off on most web browsers, but if you do this, this may affect the service that you receive from the website.
Links to other websites
Our website contains links to other websites which may be of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this Privacy Statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
Controlling your personal information
You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:
Whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want to receive information on upcoming events,
If you have previously agreed to us contacting you in this way for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at bds@ice.org.uk,
Please note that if you choose to exercise your rights to withhold data or insist on its deletion, then we may not be able to perform our duties in relation to the fulfilment of contracts relating to products and services purchased.
We will share your details with The Institution of Civil Engineers (ICE) for the purposes of Membership Applications and renewals, and for Invoicing and Payment purposes.
You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to The ICE BDS Secretary, Institution of Civil Engineers, One Great George Street, London SW1P 3AA.
If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
Your rights in relation to your data
The purpose of this Privacy Notice is to fulfil your right to be informed about the use of your data. In addition:
You have the right to access your personal data. If you wish to request copies of your personal data please contact the Data Protection Officer at the address above,
You have the right to have your data rectified if it is inaccurate or incomplete,
You have the right to have your personal data deleted or removed if there is no reason for its continued storage and processing,
You have the right to object to your personal data being processed and to restrict the processing of your personal data in certain circumstances. While processing is restricted, the data controller is permitted to store the personal data to ensure the restriction is respected in future. You will be informed if a restriction on processing is lifted,
You have the right to lodge a complaint about the data controller with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO).
Further details about GDPR and your rights under GDPR can be found at the ICO’s website at https://ico.org.uk
About
BDS Member's Area
Website Disclaimer
Privacy Policy
Copyright © 2020, British Dam Society. All rights reserved.Web site design and development by Samui Design.Admin
Privacy Policy
finish_page
